Atul Meshram

Product Designer

https://atulmeshram.github.io





m.atulmeshram@gmail.com

Bangalore, Karnataka - INDIA

Education

- **Interaction Design Specialization** University of California, San Diego 9.9 Score | Jan, 2018 | Coursera
- Master of Computer Applications NIT Karnataka, Surathkal 8.5 CGPA | May, 2016
- **GNIIT Software Engineering** NTTT

Grade - A | Apr, 2013

Bachelor of Computer Applications PRSU, Raipur 78.0% | Jun, 2011

Class 12th (Senior Secondary Edu.) CBSE - All India 81.0% | May, 2007

Skills

Design Tools

InVision Studio Sketch Adobe XD Figma Adobe After Effects FramerX ProtoPie Adobe Illustrator

Cinema 4D Flinto

User Experience

UX Research **Interaction Design** Wireframing Motion Design Rapid Prototyping Data Visualization Heuristic Evaluation A/B Testing **Usability Testing** Comparative Analysis

Programming

Visual Design

JavaScript (ES6) Flutter HTML5 **ThreeJS GSAP** CSS3 ReactJS VueJS

Leadership

Project Planning UX Strategy & Planning Team Coordination Training & Mentorship

Summary

Product designer with 4.9+ years of user-centric design experience. I enjoy interacting with people, understand their expectations and displeasing experiences from the products, and use their insights to create simple and intuitive interfaces that have a high degree of usability. Interested in immersive design and extended reality-based emerging technologies.

Experience

o9 Solutions

Bengaluru, IN

Senior UX Designer

[MAY, 2018 - Present]

- Designed and prototyped, multiple widgets and features for web, mobile, and desktop applications varying from small, one-week prototypes that explored specific interactions to large-scale, multi-month projects targeted for the launch.
- Designed intuitive, interactive, and smart analytical visual interface for the AI-based smart supply-chain platform offering features like:

Natural Language Search, Rich Data Visualization, Real-Time Collaboration, Connected Excel, Mobile Experience, Geo Map & Network, Integrated Email, Online Meeting and Presentation, and Favorite Management.

Case Study: https://atulmeshram.github.io/o9-solutions.html

Accolite Software

Bengaluru, IN

UX Designer

[JUL, 2016 - MAR, 2018]

Worked for various products at client locations. Analyzed, prototyped, and delivered the designs as per client's design requirements.

Standard Chartered Banking App [NOV, 2017 - MAR, 2018]

A mobile app for managing finances anytime anywhere.

Designed UI to offer UPI based transactions to facilitate safe, easy & instant digital payments.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/ryNkoPX

FedEx FRMS iPad App

[SEP 2017 - NOV 2017]

An iPad app for FedEx's Pilot Fatigue Management.

Analyzed existing web application and redesigned the workflow for the app.

Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes, UI design assets distribution, application flow, animations, and design guide for the developers.

BT Business App

[JUL 2016 - OCT 2017]

A business service mobile app for users offering with features to view bills, check accounts, test broadband speed, track orders, and faults.

User-research, analysis, and interpretation of customer needs, to create a pleasant user experience. Designed application flow, created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/8yNkbU2 **Apple App Store:** https://cutt.ly/kyNkRFY

CASE STUDY:

https://atulmeshram.github.io/o9-solutions.html